<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: movie | linpx & sourrabbit]]></title>
  <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/categories/movie/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-05T00:09:33+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lin Pengxuan; Dong Ping]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BLOOD DIAMOND]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2007/03/08/blood-diamond/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-08T16:01:04+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2007/03/08/blood-diamond</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今天看了Blood Diamond，又被感动掉了。原谅我的复述水平，确实好看。我以为我厌倦了这些大片，但是这一部光评分就在7.8以上，让我又了解多了些东西，
不过钻石离我是远了些。制片方似乎也没把赚钱放在第一的位置，要不这不2小时半的片子就不会看的那么过瘾。尤其是老迪死时，还有那么长可以吹的，导演厚道了。</p>

<p><img src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/images/2759%0A71.jpg" alt="http://www.stuff.co.nz/images/275971.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/images/2759%0A71.jpg" alt="http://www.stuff.co.nz/images/275971.jpg" />不多说了，过一两年再看一遍。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pan's Labyrinth]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2007/02/12/pans-labyrinth/"/>
    <updated>2007-02-12T16:20:37+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2007/02/12/pans-labyrinth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>这是一部很恶心的电影，导演很变态。我还是忍不住看完。</p>

<p><img src="http://www.im%0Apawards.com/2006/posters/pans_labyrinth_ver3.jpg" alt="http://www.impawards.com/2006/posters/pans_labyrinth_ver3.jpg" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[超人归来]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/07/16/e8b685e4babae5bd92e69da5/"/>
    <updated>2006-07-16T06:27:23+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/07/16/e8b685e4babae5bd92e69da5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>1， 最早看超人是在中央电视台播放的，好像是正大综艺之后，在5点，6点之间播放的电影。当然cut成好几段了。那时和星球大战一样，直接深深触动了我幼小和纯洁的
心灵，在我体内植入了正义和公平的种子。（别骂我，我也吐了）。。。</p>

<p>2，78年的超人叫Christopher Reeves，两年前，在我刚到韩国时死了。我知道他的事情不多，只是因为95年的时候骑马落下，摔成半植物人，在卸下小
红内裤之后。之后，我才知道什么叫身残志坚。他在美国国会公开lobby支持残疾人事业，热心支持慈善，公益事业。这才叫超人。因为他所作的已经开始向制度上的缺陷挑
战，而不是单靠蛮力，一种治标不治本的东西。</p>

<p>3，Clark 和 Lois的爱情。啊，天哪，从上世纪初就不停的一直讴歌。让我吃惊，随便在街上问问，会有人相信这样的爱情的存在吗，答案是肯定的，不过不多。几
十年了，超人越来越年轻，Lois依然青春不减，说句直接点的话，在银幕上都多少岁月了，你们怎么仍然是如此小鸟依人。漫画果然是漫画。而奇笨的我，居然也相当支持。</p>

<p>（the very early Superman Couple, now are old）</p>

<p><img src="http://www.supermanhomepage.com/images/aos-1950s/jack-noel-2006.jpg" alt="The image “http://www.supermanhomepage.com/images/aos-1950s/jack-
noel-2006.jpg” cannot be displayed, because it contains
errors." /></p>

<p>4，他们说不幸的家庭各有各的不幸，幸福的家庭都是一样的。超人和蜘蛛人，哎，不要太像啊。都是有一副面具，都有自己心仪的人不能表白，都一直在旁边看着爱人投向别人
怀抱，哦，都在报社当记者，都有一个相当专业的无情了的老板，都有弱点，都会飞檐走壁，都爱穿紧身衣，唯有超人的品味独特了点，内裤外穿，我相信这和他小时候成长的环
境也是有一定的关系的。</p>

<p>5，这部电影也越来越冯小刚化了。令我记忆犹新的就是，天下无贼中，一辆卡车，刷的一下开进，考，中国移动。。。在超人中，不下4次看到使用</p>

<p>三星手机和笔记本，尽管隐晦，但是导游还是孺子可教。让我想起 Mission:Impossible III中的中国办证广告。</p>

<p><img src="http://static.flickr.com/45/190547179_cb842c7603.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>6, 又听闻playboy 邀请超人扮演者 Branden
脱衣解带，价码50万美金。考，这么多，我也脱了。还是眼球经济，知道的越多，价值就越呈几何级数狂飙。</p>

<p>7, The producers have found in Brandon Routh an ingenuous, all-American actor
who also has the smoothly contoured, planed-down looks of a comic-book hero
and is as unknown to us as was Reeve in 1978.</p>

<p>8, Superman Returns seems an essentially Christian film. Superman comes back
to earth at a time of great crisis and is virtually crucified by Luthor, using
shards of the deadly green Kryptonite crystals as nails. While he lies dying
in hospital, his mother, Martha, is among the grieving crowd, while inside the
sick room his son looks reverently at the Superman outfit lying on a chair as
if it were the prophet's raiment, the martyr's shroud or the hero's armour.
Something resembling a resurrection follows, accompanied by heavenly music,
and a nation seems to be at ease with itself again.</p>

<p>9, when talked about Batman and Superman, some guy said, " I fantasised about
being pursued by Lois Lane rather than hanging out with Robin."</p>

<p>10, 都说司考要戒网。。。。。</p>

<p>11, 世界第四届合唱比赛在厦门举行，气死了，不能去看。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black Hawk Down]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/06/09/black-hawk-down/"/>
    <updated>2006-06-09T08:35:35+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/06/09/black-hawk-down</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今天又看了一遍黑鹰坠落。相当震撼，完了有一句话直接无语掉。</p>

<p>During the raid over 1000 Somalis died and 19 American soldiers lost their
lives.</p>

<p>这是什么样的军事实力。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[作者：乌托邦]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/05/20/e4bd9ce88085efbc9ae4b98ce68998e982a6/"/>
    <updated>2006-05-20T01:28:54+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/05/20/e4bd9ce88085efbc9ae4b98ce68998e982a6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>已经是第二次看这部电影了。 a man for all seasons.</p>

<p>then did I find out this is one of the best movies ever according to some
objective standards.</p>

<p>that I was a convinced again by the beauty of his simplicity yet confident and
reasonable tones.</p>

<p>that again I have questioned myself wow, still a long way to go with no signs
of ending.</p>

<p><img src="http://static.flickr.com/53/149549046_ee1d1d8931.jpg?v=0" alt="" /></p>

<p>It is already beyond some conflict between fire and bloods, sometimes, words
can touch your sense much more than what you thought. and poor hollywood and
shallow me, besides, after a whole bunch of years developing, what they can
present to us are nothing but sound and images.</p>

<p>Then I did a little bit research. u guys know the little annoying and ugly
Richard Rich in the movie, he is the one that plays as Chancellor again in you
know what, V for Vendetta.</p>

<p>Sir Thomas More (1477 - 1535)</p>

<p>Thomas More - lawyer, prolific writer, MP and statesman - was Chancellor of
England between 1529 and 1532. He rose to prominence early in the 16th century
as Under-sheriff of London and one of Henry VIII's most effective and trusted
civil servants, acting as the King's secretary, interpreter, speech-writer,
chief diplomat, advisor and confidant. In 1521 he was made the Kingdom's
Undertreasurer and knighted, and in 1523 he became the Speaker of the House of
Commons.</p>

<p>At the same time More was building up a reputation as one of Europe's leading
scholars. He was close to the radical catholic theologian Erasmus, but wrote
polemics against Martin Luther and the protestant reformation. Around 1515 he
wrote The History of Richard III which established that king's reputation as a
tyrant and has been described as the first masterpiece of English
historiography; and in 1516 published his most important work Utopia - a
description of an imaginary communist republic ruled by reason and intended to
contrast sharply with the strife-ridden reality of contemporary Europe
politics.</p>

<p>Despite his own free-thinking, More was a passionate defender of Catholic
orthodoxy - writing pamphlet after pamphlet against heresy, banning and
confiscating unorthodox books, and even taking personal responsibility when
Chancellor for the interrogation, whipping and burning of English heretics.</p>

<p>More took on the post of Lord Chancellor just when King Henry had become
determined to obtain a divorce from Catherine of Aragon, something forbidden
by church law. The previous Chancellor, Lord Wolsey, had failed to achieve
this objective, Henry was close to breaking with the Church of Rome, and the
so-called 'Reformation Parliament' was about to convene. More was opposed to
Henry's policy.</p>

<p>When Henry declared himself 'Supreme Head of the Church in England' - thus
establishing the Anglican Church and allowing him to set aside his marriage -
More resigned the Chancellorship to be replaced as the King's main advisor by
Thomas Cromwell. He continued to argue against the King's divorce and the
split with Rome, and in 1534 was arrested after refusing to swear an Oath of
Succession repudiating the Pope and accepting the annulment of the marriage to
Catherine. Fifteen months later More was tried for treason at Westminster, and
on July 6th 1535 he was executed by beheading on Tower Hill.</p>

<p>In 1935 Thomas More was recognised as a catholic saint.</p>

<p><img src="http://images.amazon.com/images/P/6305252564.01._PE33_.A%0A-Man-for-All-Seasons._SCLZZZZZZZ_.jpg" alt="http://images.amazon.com/images/P/6305252564.01._PE33_.A-Man-for-All-Seasons
._SCLZZZZZZZ_.jpg" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
