<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: job | linpx & sourrabbit]]></title>
  <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/categories/job/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-05T00:09:33+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lin Pengxuan; Dong Ping]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[a word from Mark Twain]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2007/06/22/a-word-from-mark-twain/"/>
    <updated>2007-06-22T07:22:56+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2007/06/22/a-word-from-mark-twain</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今天看书，有一句话特别那个。。。那个是什么，我也说不清，反正就是那个。。。</p>

<p>October is one of the peculiar dangerous months to do speculate in stocks, the
others are July, January, Septermber, April, November, May, August, March,
June, December and February.</p>

<p>入市有风险，炒股需谨慎。股票风险的控制，我也不知道该如何控制，但我觉得比较合适的方式就是，如果你晚上睡觉时根本不会去想，去担心你白天买的股票时，也就差不多了
。</p>

<p>下午帮老板打电话去航空里程找密码，图方便，直接和小姐说我就是老板。差点被识破，问了生日，电邮等，还好手头上有资料。结果最后一个问题，我最近作哪一班飞机去哪里
，直接无法回答。于是，我说，你等一下，我叫我秘书回答你，我现在接个电话。然后就叫anny回答。在然后呢，对方又叫anny把电话给我，然后说密码只能告诉我本人
。。。</p>

<p>打完电话，想一想，突然很郁闷，因为我老板是61年生人。我的声音很老吗/？</p>

<p>-- <br/>
Sincerely,</p>

<p>Lin Pengxuan</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[今天股票开始割肉]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2007/03/05/e4bb8ae5a4a9e882a1e7a5a8e5bc80e5a78be589b2e88289/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-05T04:00:03+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2007/03/05/e4bb8ae5a4a9e882a1e7a5a8e5bc80e5a78be589b2e88289</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>大盘已经跌了很久。今天卖正股股票割肉，两支平均亏了8%。</p>

<p>现在就是希望股市一直跌，要是因为两会又升回去了，我只能说运气不好了。</p>

<p>今天选的9966，一个下午涨40%。只要中国银行在今年8月份的之间涨多6毛，我的权证就能挣30万。期待中。说到底，还是赌博。本金，嘿嘿，从买的时候我就打定主
意，这5万块不要了。这叫泰然。清心无欲，无欲则刚。</p>

<p>算了，说说我咋选的。权证和正股是不一样的，有兴趣的人自己去查查就会发现，哦，挣钱还可以这样啊。前些天网上有人说用800块买权证挣到50万。我不知道是怎么做的
，尽管看了解释，但是我想应该是可能的。</p>

<p>我只炒3只股票，其他一概不看。为什么？因为不熟。8276，世纪阳光。它是上年度香港创业板唯一几只值得炒的，我很庆幸，回国后眼睁着看他从4块涨到10块，但是我
知炒这支股票的机会成本是100万，至于为什么，以后再说。3988，中国银行。市场再怎么跌，这支都会屹立不倒。为什么，因为背后有中国政府。0762，中国联通。
我对它起重视，是因为它和3g有关。</p>

<p>9966是8月份中国银行权证到期中成本最低的，，只有3块6，也就是现在的价格，只要看看其他一个月后到期的权证成本就是4块，就感觉到不买真是亏了。升多两毛，回
本，剩下数钱。开始注意它是上个月，那时没人买，都是庄家自己在炒。我没有那么多股票理论，那么多线都看不懂。所以买好就放哪。它也争气，今天早上又买2万5千块钱，
下午就给你回报5千块，10分钟后回报8千块，刚刚收盘，价值上升一万。但是我抓不住机会的能力是相当出名的，我知不会卖的。</p>

<p>另外就是对大盘的看法。当真正到全民炒股的时候，就是很可怕的时候。所以上周二的历史最大跌幅，照我看是好事。第一赶掉一些人。第二，价格下降好建仓。</p>

<hr />

<p>然后是3988中国银行正股涨多4分钱，意味着我的权证还要从2毛3涨到2毛7，成本仅为1毛8。网上说是技术调整，我怎么看都不像。</p>

<p>可恨的是，我一开始割肉，第二天正股就涨回。难受啊。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[10分钟赚了些]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/11/17/10e58886e9929fe8b59ae4ba86e4ba9b/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-17T03:33:47+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/11/17/10e58886e9929fe8b59ae4ba86e4ba9b</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[炒股]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/11/16/e78292e882a1/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-16T07:26:16+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/11/16/e78292e882a1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>这一周炒股挣了些钱。小现一下。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[working smart]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/03/01/working-smart/"/>
    <updated>2006-03-01T02:07:22+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/03/01/working-smart</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>this one I took it from <a href="http://www.michaelhyatt.com/workingsmart/2006/02/whats_the_secre.html">http://www.michaelhyatt.com
</a>,
which I think a good guide for those who want to get a good job....</p>

<h3>What’s the Secret to Your Success?</h3>

<p>As a CEO, I get asked this a lot. And, I'm always a little embarrassed by it.
For the most part, I get the question from people who are in their twenties.
They want to know “the secret path to the top.”</p>

<p>This past weekend, I received an email from one of my readers. He started, “I
have an MBA, but I must have missed the course on Fast-Tracking My Career. If
you had to boil it down to one thing, Mr. Hyatt, what would you recommend to a
young, aspiring person such as myself?”</p>

<p>I'm not sure I could boil it down to one thing. Life isn’t usually that
simple. But if I really, really had to boil it down to one thing, I would say
this: <em>responsiveness.</em></p>

<p>So many people I meet are unresponsive. They don’t return their phone calls
promptly. They don’t answer their emails quickly. They don’t complete their
assignments on time. They promise to do something and never follow through.
They have to be reminded, prodded, and nagged. This behavior creates work for
everyone else and eats into their own productivity. Sadly, they seem oblivious
to it.</p>

<p>When I was a kid, we used to play “Tag.” The objective was simple: keep from
becoming “It.” If someone tagged you (touched you), you became “it” until you
tagged someone else. Whoever was “it” when the game ended, lost.</p>

<p>Business is very similar. People “tag” us in countless ways every day. They
place calls. They send emails. They mention something to us in a meeting.
Suddenly, we are “it.” And, just like the game, if you stay “it” too long, you
lose. The only winning strategy is to respond quickly and make someone else
“it.”</p>

<p>Reality is that we live in an “instant world.” People want instant results.
They don’t want to wait. And if they have to wait on you, their frustration
and resentment grows. They begin to see you as an <em>obstacle</em> to getting their
work done. If that happens, it will begin to impact your reputation. Pretty
soon people start saying, “I can never get a timely response from him,” or
“When I send her an email, I feel like it goes into a black hole,” or worse,
your colleagues just roll their eyes and sigh at the mention of your name.</p>

<p>Yet, these are the very people who will push you up or pull you down. You
cannot succeed without the support of your peers and subordinates. (Go back
and re-read that sentence again.)</p>

<p>As I was making my way to the top, my former boss, Sam Moore, used to ask
everyone I worked with, “What’s it like to work with Mike?” “How’s he really
doing?” “Do you think he could take on more responsibility?” In responding to
him, all they had was their experience with me. If I hadn’t been responsive to
them, how do you think they would have responded to his questions? “More
responsibility? Are you kidding me? He can’t handle what he has now!” It
wouldn’t take too many candid responses like that to tank my career.</p>

<p>And yet this happens to people all the time. I can’t tell you how many
meetings I have sat in where people are complaining about someone else’s work
habits. “He always waits until the last minute.” “She never plans ahead.” “I
can never get him to respond to my emails.” You may think that the people who
are making these comments are too far down the food chain to matter. I can
assure you they aren’t. They have a way of bubbling to the top where the
decisions about your career are made.</p>

<p>The truth is, you are building your reputation—your brand—<em>one response at a
time.</em> People are shaping their view of you by how you respond to them. If you
are slow, they assume you are incompetent and over your head. If you respond
quickly, they assume you are competent and on top of your work. Their
perception, whether you realize it or not, will determine how fast your career
advances and how high you go. You can’t afford to be unresponsive. It is a
career-killer.</p>

<p>My basic rule is this: respond immediately unless there is a good reason to
wait. Obviously, this isn’t always possible, especially since I spend so much
time in meetings. Nevertheless, I rarely let messages sit longer than a day.
Twenty-four hours is the outside edge. If you can’t respond now, then at least
acknowledge that you have received the message: “I received your message. I
don’t have time to give it the attention it deserves right now, but you can
expect to hear from me before the end of the day tomorrow.”</p>

<p>The great thing about being responsive is that it will quickly differentiate
you from your peers. People love doing business with responsive people.
Nothing will advance your career faster than this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
