<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: reading time | linpx & sourrabbit]]></title>
  <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/categories/reading-time/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-05T00:09:33+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lin Pengxuan; Dong Ping]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[阅读：Steve Jobs ]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2011/11/14/e99885e8afbbefbc9asteve-jobs-reading/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-14T13:04:40+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2011/11/14/e99885e8afbbefbc9asteve-jobs-reading</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
<li>看完了乔布斯传。</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/41lGhIX733L._SL500_AA300_.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<ol>
<li><p>有些长。最后脚注长达20%。最后一章已经几近无耐心地扫完。</p></li>
<li><p>共耗时2周多些，利用上下班空余时间。</p></li>
<li><p>书不错。学到的地方是，一定要focus。把不必要的细节全部删除。</p></li>
<li><p>第一次在amazon上买书，有时可以利用android的同步来进行阅读。正在考虑是否要保持这样看书的方式，除了一些书本购买的费用外，我实在看不出不这样
做的原因。</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[u freak?]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/06/07/u-freak/"/>
    <updated>2006-06-07T01:23:53+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/06/07/u-freak</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>tired of preparing my bar, not wanting to keep wasting my time either, I
decided to read some books. I bought 4 books last weeks.</p>

<p>1, <a href="http://www.freakonomics.com/">freakonomics</a>.</p>

<p>2, <a href="http://www.answers.com/main/ntquery?s=the+world+is+flat&amp;gwp=13">the world is
flat.</a> <a href="http://guancha.gmw.cn/show.aspx?id=2566">clip
2</a></p>

<p>3, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rich_Dad,_Poor_Dad">rich daddy, poor daddy.</a></p>

<p>4,<a href="http://www.powells.com/cgi-%0Abin/biblio?isbn=1569244197"> too soon old, too late smart</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://content.answers.com/main/content/wp/en/6/63/Freakonomics.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>I have a good taste, havn't I? yeah, nor really running for fictions, rather,
I prefer to be exposed with something that might help me on my way ahead.</p>

<p>Let me just done the talking. It took me 4 days finishing the 1st book,
freakonomics. to be frank, I like this book. It is all about the ways breaking
conventional wisdom that chained on us for far too long a time. what I can see
there is just a little bit different way of thinking could result in an
astonishing situation.</p>

<p>what do chicago public school teachers and sumo wrestlers have in common? why
do most drug dealers in American still live with their moms?</p>

<p> how do people's names affect their personal success?</p>

<p>...</p>

<p>these are some common things that people won't even raise an eyebrow if they
are not curious enough, or should we say, they are, at least not just acting
like authors of this book. after matrixing a bunch of datas, they manage to
quantify these culture phenomenons. you believe that? Becasue I do, after
reading this book.</p>

<p>It has something to do with sensibly thinking about how people do in real
world, not a moral and ideal world. so for those who have suffered enough,
they won't feel the intended unfortabilities brought by authors.</p>

<p>I agree reading is really boring. but it is cool.</p>

<p>P.S. know freakonomic= freak+ economics, it just was a way of making new words
without turning to dictionaries.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[一些小书]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/04/09/e4b880e4ba9be5b08fe4b9a6/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-09T14:33:27+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/04/09/e4b880e4ba9be5b08fe4b9a6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>最近读些闲书。 方平的
<a href="http://www.tycool.com/bbs/showthread.php?t=8311&amp;page=1&amp;pp=10">半夏</a></p>

<p>烟雨江南的 <a href="http://www.cmfu.com/readbook.asp?bl_id=5060"> 亵渎</a></p>

<p>很推荐。也没有那么多时间解释有多好。随便电击看个开头吧。特点是，开头很好看，越看越好看，到后面巨好看。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[confession of Economy Hit Man]]></title>
    <link href="http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/02/08/confession-of-economy-hit-man/"/>
    <updated>2006-02-08T08:48:22+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://linpengxuan.github.com/octopress/blog/2006/02/08/confession-of-economy-hit-man</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>@page {size:21cm 29.7cm;margin:2cm;} P {margin-bottom:0.21cm;}</p>

<p>今天听了本小说《the confession of an EHM》，里面对Muslim的世界观有个说法。</p>

<p>The Americans want to take control the whole world. And now it could not be a
better time doing it for it is already pretty much close to that point. USSR
may stand on its way, but will prove to be destructive.(it was been proved in
1990) the competition in the future would not between the communism and
capitalism but a war of faith, a war between Muslim and Christian. History has
proved this several times. Ideology couldn't do anything, take a look at USSR,
it has no substance, no economy, no faith, it was set up to doom. There are no
other things in the world more faithful than Muslim world. So right now we
wait, till we grow stronger, then we fight like a snake......</p>

<p>oops.听到这心里都有一阵异样的感觉，联系到最近的丹麦政治漫画。突然感觉拉登的做法不过是Muslim世界里的一种极端，但是却体现了这种思想的一种行为。</p>

<p>EHM，economy hit man. Usually disguise as employee of multinational corporation
been deployed over the world after world war II when arms conflict prove to be
not a good solution in resolving dispute related to resource in cold war
times. When they failed their mission, and their successor fail either, say,
jack man, war would be the final but only solution. The first and second gulf
war, the 1967 war between Israel and Egypt....</p>

<p>following is another excerpt by Bill Clinton who cited from Mr. Churchill.
American would always find the best way to solve the problem only after it
exhaustive all the other alternatives.</p>

<p>and do we have to?</p>

<p><img src="http://survivalcenter.com/images/EconHitMan.jpg" alt="The image “http://survivalcenter.com/images/EconHitMan.jpg” cannot be
displayed, because it contains
errors." /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
